Guide to the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York Records 1785-2014 MS 2997
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Membership Records (RESTRICTIONS APPLY), circa 1820-2000s
  - Subseries III.1: Registers, circa 1820-1987
    - Biographical register of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York, Vol. 1 1756 - 1806, 1922 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 91)
    - Register of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York. Third Series, 1857 - 1906, 1923 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 92)
    - Biographical register of Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York. Vol. 2, 1807 - 1856, 1925 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 93)
    - Supplementary list of members, circa 1855 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6)
    - Membership lists copied from early documents, 1770 - 1820, 1915 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 6-A)
    - Honorary members, circa 1940 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 7)
    - Typescript register, 1907 - 1919, circa 1920 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8)
    - Membership roster, 1987 (Offsite-box 33, Folder 8-A)
    - Duplicate member lists, 1855, 1987 (Offsite-box 97)
  - Subseries III.2: Member Applications, 1878-1962
    Member applications contain information about individuals wishing to join the Society. Volumes are arranged chronologically. Within the volumes, however, the applications are organized alphabetically by name. See also the subseries Member Files, which contains unbound applications.
    - Propositions for Membership, 1878 - 1897 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 94)
    - Propositions for Membership, 1895 - 1897 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 95)
    - Proposals for Membership. Duplicate Missing Records of members on the roll 1846 - 1908, 1910 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 96)
    - Proposals for Membership, 1897 - 1905 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 97)
    - Proposals for Membership, 1905 - 1909 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 98)
    - Proposals for Membership, 1910 - 1914 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 99)
    - Applications for Membership, 1915 - 1917 (Offsite-box SA-10, Volume 100)
    - Applications for Membership, 1918 - 1920 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 101)
    - Applications for Membership, 1921 - 1923 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 102)
    - Applications for Membership, 1924 - 1925 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 103)
    - Applications for Membership, 1926 - 1928 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 104)
    - Applications for Membership, 1928 - 1935 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 105)
    - Applications for Membership, 1935 - 1937 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 106)
    - Applications for Membership, 1937 - 1941 (Offsite-box SA-11, Volume 107)
    - Applications for Membership, 1942 - 1945 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 108)
    - Applications for Membership, 1946 - 1948 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 109)
    - Applications for Membership, 1949 - 1951 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 110)
    - Applications for Membership, 1951 - 1954 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 111)
    - Applications for Membership, 1954 - 1956 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 112)
    - Applications for Membership, 1956 - 1962 (Offsite-box SA-12, Volume 113)
  - Subseries III.3: Archived Member Files, 1850s - 2000s
    Member Files contain application materials and correspondence related to an individual's involvement in the Society. All refer to inactive members. "Archived" Member Files reflect the filing system from about the 1990s to the time of accession. They therefore include the files of members active in the 1990s and 2000s. Additionally, many earlier member files, primarily although not exclusively those with last names beginning with 'A' through 'C', had been interfiled into this subseries. See also the following subseries Unarchived Member Files.
    - Abercrombie, David - Anderson, Edmund (Offsite-box 34)
    - Anderson, Edward - Azoy, Philip (Offsite-box 35)
    - Bacon, James - Beaton, Douglas (Offsite-box 36)
    - Beaton, Farquhar - Blair, William (Offsite-box 37)
    - Blanchard, James - Browne, Stewart (Offsite-box 38)
    - Brownlee, John - Callender, Thomas (Offsite-box 39)
    - Callender, Walter - Campbell, Rolla (Offsite-box 40)
    - Campbell, Ronald - Clark, Peter (Offsite-box 41)
    - Clark, Robert - Douglass, Robert (Offsite-box 42)
    - Dow, Ian - Gilmore, Jere (Offsite-box 43)
    - Gilmour, John - Irving, William (Offsite-box 44)
    - Jacobs, Iain - MacDonald, Donald (Offsite-box 45)
    - MacDonald, Hugh - McAulay, Archibald (Offsite-box 46)
    - McAusland, John - Moore, Stratford (Offsite-box 47)
    - Morgan, Scott - Ritchie, Paul (Offsite-box 48)
    - Robb, Ian - Stitt, Robert (Offsite-box 49)
    - Stoddart, John - Zier, Dennis (Offsite-box 50)
  - Subseries III.4: Unarchived Member Files, 1850s - 1980s
    Member Files contain application materials and correspondence related to an individual's involvement in the Society. All refer to inactive members. "Unarchived" Member Files reflect the filing system from about the 1850s to the 1980s, and the files remain housed in their original envelopes. See also previous subseries Archived Member Files.
    - Adams, Thomas - Delafield, Maturin (Offsite-box 51)
    - Demarest - Esplin (Offsite-box 52)
    - Evans - Fyshe (Offsite-box 53)
    - Gair - Gravill (Offsite-box 54)
    - Gray - Hoffman (Offsite-box 55)
    - Hogarth - Kelso (Offsite-box 56)
    - Kemp - Love (Offsite-box 57)
    - Low - MacKaye (Offsite-box 58)
    - MacKecknie - Marshall (Offsite-box 59)
    - Marston - McIver (Offsite-box 60)
    - McKay - Milligan (Offsite-box 61)
    - Mills - Neill (Offsite-box 62)
    - Neilson - Purrington (Offsite-box 63)
    - Purves - Rutherford (Offsite-box 64)
    - Rutherfurd - Spence (Offsite-box 65)
    - Spencer - Thompson (Offsite-box 66)
    - Thoms - Weber (Offsite-box 67)
    - Webster - Zealand (Offsite-box 68)
- Series IV: Event Records, 1893-2014
  Records of events held by the Society contain ephemera and transcripts from Anniversary Banquets, memos and correspondence involved in the planning of various events, and photographs of the events themselves.
  - Subseries IV.1: Anniversary Banquet Proceedings, 1893-1989 (Offsite-box SA-15, Volume 115)
    This subseries contains ephemera and transcriptions of the proceedings at the Society's Anniversary Banquets. Included are menus, programs that detail guests and seating arrangements, and in some cases, the text of speeches given on the occasion. Bound volumes are arranged first, followed by foldered material. Duplicate items are housed separately.
    - Speeches delivered at 157th anniversary dinner, 1913 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 114)
    - Anniversary banquet speeches and proceedings, 1936 - 1962 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 115)
    - Anniversary banquet speeches and proceedings, 1963 - 1976 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 116)
    - Menus and programs, 1893 - 1898 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 1)
    - Menus and programs, 1899 - 1902 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 1a)
    - Menu, program, and speeches, 1903 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 2)
    - Menu, program, and speeches, 1904 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 3)
    - Program and speeches, 1905 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 4)
    - Program and speeches, 1906 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 5)
    - Menu and program, 1907 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 6)
    - Program and speeches, 1908 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 7)
    - Menu and programs, 1910 - 1911 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 8)
    - Menus and programs, 1912 - 1914 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 9)
    - Menus and programs, 1916, 1918 - 1919 (Offsite-box 95 (tall box), Folder 1, Offsite-box 69, Folder 10)
    - Menus and programs, 1920 - 1922 (Offsite-box 69, Folder 11)
    - Menus and programs, 1923 - 1925 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 1)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1926 - 1927 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 2)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1928 - 1929 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 3)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1930 - 1931 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 4)
    - Menu, program, and speeches, 1932 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 5)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1933, 1935 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 6)
    - Menus and programs, 1936 - 1937 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 7)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1938 - 1939 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 8)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1940 - 1941 (Offsite-box 70, Folder 9)
    - Menus and program, 1942 - 1944 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 1)
    - Menu, programs, and speeches, 1945 - 1947 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 2)
    - Menus, program, and speeches, 1949 - 1950 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 3)
    - Menus and program, 1951 - 1953 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 4)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1954 - 1955 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 5)
    - Menu, program, and speeches, 1956 - 1957 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 6)
    - Menus, program, and speeches, 1958 - 1959 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 7)
    - Menus and program, 1960 - 1962 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 8)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1963 - 1964 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 9)
    - Menus, program, and speeches, 1965 - 1966 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 10)
    - Menus, programs, speeches, and invitation, 1967 - 1969 (Offsite-box 71, Folder 11)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1970 - 1971 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 1)
    - Menus, programs, and speeches, 1972 - 1973 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 2)
    - Menus, programs, invitation, and speeches, 1974 - 1975 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 3)
    - Menus, programs, invitation, and speeches, 1976 - 1977 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 4)
    - Programs, invitation, and speeches, 1978 - 1979 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 5)
    - Menus and programs, 1980 - 1981 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 6)
    - Menu and programs, 1982 - 1984 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 7)
    - Menus, programs, and invitations, 1985, 1987 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 8)
    - Menu and speeches, 1988 - 1989 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 9)
    - Duplicate banquet material, 1905 - 1985 (Offsite-box 98)
  - Subseries IV.2: Event Committee Records, 1947-2002
    This subseries contains records produced by the committees responsible for organizing events held by the Society. The primary events concerned are the Anniversary Banquets, Golf Tournaments, and Tartan Balls. Material is arranged chronologially.
    - Golf Tournament, 1947 - 1949 (Offsite-box 72, Folder 10)
    - Glee Club, 1949 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 1)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1950 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 2)
    - Golf Tournament, 1950 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 3)
    - Golf Tournament, 1951 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 4)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1951 - 1953, 1955 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 5)
    - Golf Tournament, 1952 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 6)
    - Golf Tournament, 1953 - 1955 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 7)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1953 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 8)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1954 - 1956 (Offsite-box 73, Folder 9)
    - Anniversary Banquet, Bicentennial, 1956 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 1)
    - Anniversary Banquet, Bicentennial, 1956 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 2)
    - Anniversary Banquet, Bicentennial, 1956 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 3)
    - Anniversary Banquet, Bicentennial, 1956 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 4)
    - Golf Tournament, 1956 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 5)
    - Commonwealth Ball, 1957 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 6)
    - Golf Tournament, 1957 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 7)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1957 - 1962 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 8)
    - Golf Tournament, 1958 - 1959 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 9)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1958 - 1959 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 10)
    - Golf Tournament, 1960 (Offsite-box 74, Folder 11)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1960 - 1961 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 1)
    - Golf Tournament, 1961 - 1963 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 2)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1962 - 1963 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 3)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1963 - 1967 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 4)
    - Golf Tournament, 1968 - 1979 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 5)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1968, 1970 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 6)
    - Burns Society, 1969 - 1972 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 7)
    - The Black Watch, Scottish Games, and Gathering of the Clans, 1970 - 1979 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 7a)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1971 - 1973 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 8)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1974 - 1976 (Offsite-box 75, Folder 9)
    - Spring Dinner Dance, 1974 - 1979 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 1)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1977 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 2)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1977 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 3)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1978 - 1979 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 4)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1980 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 5)
    - Spring Dinner Dance and Tartan Ball, 1980 - 1982 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 6)
    - Highland Games, 1980 - 1982 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 7)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1981 (Offsite-box 76, Folder 8)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1981 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 1)
    - The Players, 1981 - 1982 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 2)
    - Burns Society, 1982 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 3)
    - Golf Outing, 1982 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 4)
    - Tartan Ball, 1983 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 5)
    - Glenfiddich Games, 1983 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 6)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1984 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 7)
    - Tartan Ball, 1984 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 8)
    - Tartan Ball, 1984 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 9)
    - Tartan Ball, 1985 (Offsite-box 77, Folder 10)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 1985 - 1986 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 1)
    - Tartan Ball, 1986 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 2)
    - Tartan Ball, 1986 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 3)
    - Golf Outing, 1986 - 1991 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 4)
    - Tartan Ball, 1987 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 5)
    - Tartan Ball, 1987 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 6)
    - Scotland Golf Outing, 1987 - 1988 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 7)
    - Tartan Ball, 1988 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 8)
    - Tartan Ball, 1988 (Offsite-box 78, Folder 9)
    - Tartan Ball, 1989 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 1)
    - Tartan Ball, 1989 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 2)
    - Tartan Ball, 1989 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 3)
    - Whiskey Tasting, 1989 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 4)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 2002 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 5)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 2002 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 6)
    - Anniversary Banquet, 2002 (Offsite-box 79, Folder 7)
    - Duplicate Tartan Ball and Anniversary Banquet committee records, 1977 - 2002 (Offsite-box 97)
  - Subseries IV.3: Photographs, 1935-2014
    This subseries contains photographs documenting the social and cultural events held by the society. The majority are focused on Anniversary Banquets and gatherings related to Tartan Week.
    The photographs are arranged in rough chronological order. Loose photographs and photograph albums are housed together.
    - Event photographs, circa 1950 - 1969 (Offsite-box 80, Offsite-box 81)
    - Event photographs, 1979 - 1989 (Offsite-box 82)
    - Event photographs, 1990 - 1994 (Offsite-box 83)
    - Event photographs, 1995 - 1999 (Offsite-box 84)
    - Event photographs, 2000 - 2004 (Offsite-box 85)
    - Event photographs, 2005 - 2006 (Offsite-box 86)
    - Event photographs, 2007 - 2008 (Offsite-box 87)
    - Event photographs, 2009 - 2012 (Offsite-box 88)
    - Event photographs, 2013 - 2014, undated (Offsite-box 89)
    - Oversize photographs, 1935 - 1950 (Offsite-box 100, Folder SASNY OS 1)
    - Oversize photographs, 1950 - 1965 (Offsite-box 100, Folder SASNY OS 2)
- Series V: The Pibroch, 1944-1994
  The Pibroch was the newsletter published by the Saint Andrew's Society of the State of New York from 1944 to 1994. It featured reviews of meetings, member news, reports from officers, pieces of cultural and historical interest, and information related to social events.
  The series is divided into two subseries. The first subseries consists of the published issues of the Pibroch. The second subseries, publication records, contains files held by the editor of the Pibroch. The Recording Secretary was typically responsible for editing the newsletter, and the files include mockups, page proofs, clippings, copyright forms, and correspondence. Material is arranged chronologically within each subseries.
  - Subseries V.1: Published Issues, 1944-1994
    - The Pibroch, volume I, 1944 - 1955 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 117)
    - The Pibroch, volume II, numbers 1-15, 1956 - 1963 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 118)
    - The Pibroch, volume II, numbers 16-30, 1963 - 1970 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 119)
    - The Pibroch, volume III, numbers 1-14, 1971 - 1977 (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 120)
    - The Pibroch, volume V-X, 1978 April - 1989 May (Offsite-box SA-13, Volume 121)
    - The Pibroch, volume X, numbers 4-6, 8, 1989 November - 1991 November (Offsite-box 90, Folder 1)
    - The Pibroch, volume XI, numbers 1-3, 1992 August - 1994 December (Offsite-box 90, Folder 1)
    - Duplicate issues, 1956 April - 1989 May (Offsite-box 99)
  - Subseries V.2: Publication Records, 1944-1973
    - The Pibroch, 1944 - 1950 April (Offsite-box 90)
    - The Pibroch, 1950 October - 1955 October (Offsite-box 91)
    - The Pibroch, 1956 - 1967 (Offsite-box 92)
    - The Pibroch, 1968 - 1973 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 1-2)
- Series VI: Miscellaneous Historical Material, 1744-1992
  Miscellaneous Historical Material contains items of historical value informally collected by the Society. While direct historical documentation such as constitutions or printed histories is contained primarily in the Administrative Records series, this series gathers material such as clippings, reproductions, photographs, and printed matter that complements material found elsewhere in the collection.
  - Subseries VI.1: Related Organizations, 1744-1981
    Material from Saint Andrew's Societies based in other locations contexualizes the work of the Saint Andrew's Society in New York. Items are arranged chonologically.
    - Photocopy of "Rules and Orders agreed upon by the Scots Society in New-York", 1744 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - The constitution and rules of the St. Andrew's Society in Philadelphia, 1769 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - The constitution of the Dumfries and Galloway Society of the City of New-York, 1807 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Saint Andrew's Society of Savannah, Georgia, 1913 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - 175th Annual Dinner of the Saint Andrews Society [Philadelphia], 1924 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 3)
    - An historical sketch of the St. Andrew's Society of Philadelphia, 1931 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 4)
    - [The St. Andrew's Society of Montreal history and information], [1973] (Offsite-box 93, Folder 4)
    - The St. Andrew's Society of Winnipeg news letter no. 4, 1981 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 4)
  - Subseries VI.2: Clippings and Ephemera, 1836-1992
    Reproductions, scrapbooks, clippings, and ephemera span nearly the full history of the institution.
    - Transcriptions of material from 1785 - 1794 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 5)
    - Photocopies of indenture (Offsite-box 100, Folder SASNY OS 3)
    - Scrapbook compiled by George Austin Morrison Jr., 1836 - 1894 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 6-7)
    - Media clippings, 1912 - 1983 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 8)
    - Ephemera related to Saint Andrew's Society and its members, 1900 - 1992 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 9)
      Includes signed menu, certificate, booklet from Central Park monument restoration, and other material.
    - Booklets and souveniers not related to Saint Andrew's Society, circa 1950 - 1970 (Offsite-box 93, Folder 10)
    - Printed matter related to Scottish subjects, 1944 - 1960 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 1)
    - Woodblock and printed banquet image, circa 1950 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 2)
    - Matted clippings from Bicentennial Exhibition, 1956 (Offsite-box 95 (tall box), Folder 1a)
    - Scrapbook of material related to victims of September 11 attack (Offsite-box 100, Folder SASNY OS 4)
    - Duplicate ephemera (Offsite-box 97)
  - Subseries VI.3: Photographs, 1950s-1960s, undated
    Miscellaneous photographs include portraits, meeting photographs, and images of places and occasions related to the activities of the Society.
    - Presidents and miscellaneous photographs (Offsite-box 94, Folder 3)
    - Meeting photographs, circa 1960 (Offsite-box 94, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous historical photographs (Offsite-box 94, Folder 5)
    - Matted photographs from Bicentennial Exhibition, 1956 (Offsite-box 95 (tall box), Folder 2-6)
    - Oversize photographs (Offsite-box 95 (tall box), Folder 7)
    - Oversize photographs (Offsite-box 100, Folder SASNY OS3)